Hello, all my friends, and welcome to exercise number 60.
We are asked to write a function that insert notes after a given note in W Link at list.
So how to make a function that inserts notes before giving them note?
The user give us a note and we need to insert this note after a specific note he gives us.
So we issued the two parameter.
Their previous note that we are going to insert a new note after it and the data of the newly created
note we have seen in the previous videos that we have created the note of the double anchored list.
And here is the section of the lists and methods that we have created and every section and every method
contains its own exercise they know in exercise.
No, this is exercise no.16.
I will create public void insert insert after after this took into parameter the the previous note that
we are going to insert the data or the newly created note after it and end new date.
This is the new and note or the data of the new note check.
If they're given a previous note is not the first step.
Check if I am inserting like into an empty list.
Or any link in the list empty, no notes or I am inserting into are none found.
Note.
OK.
So I should be accurate by this, by providing a check if they're given proof.
No, there's not.
How to check that?
If previous note equal equal to none, then this is none.
And the system ducked out dirt print and that given that given
previous.
No, it is not.
And what to do?
We need to repair.
This is how we protect our algorithm from making anything unusual and making errors and exceptions.
OK, so second step is creating their note if it is found the previous note.
If we found it and it is not null, then we need to create this note after it.
How to do that the same way that we have done it before we create a new node band using the constructor
and you know, and we pass the new data that perimeter that we have inserted, the perimeter that we
have passed into the insert after method and we directly use it here in order to create a node with
this date.
OK.
It's very simple.
Till now, we are just creating the nodes now making the reference to the linking linked linkage so
that it's very important.
And this is the trick behind inserting after and inserting before methods.
You are asked these questions in order to see your and your ability to link the newly created nodes.
So in order to link any node we start in, we get the new node dot.
We are not interested in the date that we have done it.
We need to link it with the next and the previous.
OK.
We will start by the next equal brave node dot next.
The previous node equal dot next make at the new node.
Up next, we are just copying the code and the link of the previously created.
Let me let me demonstrate it very clearly.
You may be may get confused.
So don't worry.
So what we are doing here, we have this link, double link at least.
And these are the notes.
OK.
We are inserting a new note here.
This is new note.
We are inserting it after this.
This is called what it's called.
I'm inserting than you note between them after the one.
So what we need to do is to delete the linkage and make here.
Then next.
The next of this would be referring to the previous of this newly created note and then next of the
new note next of the new No.
So this would be the previous note, the next.
So it was then the previous note like this.
We need to copy this reference and put it here.
So this would be the newly created node would be a reference to the previous node next.
And we need to link this with the previous of it.
OK, so we are just copying the addresses, the references of the linkage and we are putting here,
where is the new node that we are creating?
So new node here Dot or the previous node?
Previous node now dot next equal to new nodes, we are referencing it to then, you know, OK?
And we need also to make new note that previous, not previous, equal to previous note, so the previous
of the new note, equal to the previous note that we are going to insert this data or the new note after
it.
So this is very simple and logical.
The first step is changing the previous of the new nodes.
Next note change the previous.
I will make it the same as here because we are making the linkage step linkage step we make for links.
Okay.
One for the previous and one for the next for each of the and newly created.
Yeah.
So if new node don't stop next does not equal to now if it is not the last one.
Then new note new node dot next door to pretty equal to new No.
OK, this is how we access and how we make the linkage step.
OK.
It's very important that we have covered these steps by creating a check.
If a given note is known, then creating the nodes and linking the linkage step.
This is a very important step and this is that context.
This is the important step of the this algorithm inserting after method.
OK.
No, since the linked list is typically represented by the head of it, we have to traverse the list
to end and then choose the next of the last note that new not OK if we are going to make a.
But if it is like the same step and this is inserting before or inserting after may be just the same
context, the same complexity.
But we will see how we can change this.
OK?
The linkage is that OK?
No.
You can test it, we can insert here the L L, the insert after I will make the doctor had I will create
the her and the after the hat, so I will insert 99.
Okay, let's see if I have inserted after the head.
Ninety nine.
OK, let me check this this here.
W. Link at best.
It is doubly linked to this.
This is for the Lincoln best.
OK.
That's Iran, and see.
Let's see.
And there we go.
Adding the new note printing in forward way one, this is the head and 99 has been inserted directly
after the hat.
So our method is working fine.